

K.BHASKAR SURI Curriculum Vitae

Mobile: India: +917702017031 Email: mailsuri2004@yahoo.com

surikovela@gmail.com
Personal Statement

A Degree holder in Hotel Management with over 15years of experience in Rooms division department. Looking forward to work in an organization that offers challenging, stimulated and team oriented environment, where the skill and knowledge can be shared and achieved to work in a progressive work culture. I maintain a high level of professionalism when working and also capable of learning new things and technology in regard to my work area.

Relevant Employment History

Currently working on MS EURODAM"Holland America Line" as a Head of Housekeeping Department. Successful in getting high ratings during USPH & Canadian audits during Alaska Itinerary in recent month.

April, 2017 - March, 2018: Radisson Blue Hotel

Director of Rooms

Worked as a director of rooms for front of office, spa, horticulture, housekeeping & laundry department. Looking after all the housekeeping & laundry operations. Managing housekeeping supervisors & their teams by working in closely with them, making sure everything is well maintained as per the standard of the company. Inspecting all the laundry machines, equipment's, & chemical lockers. Rebuilt the Standard Operating Procedure as per the company standards.

February 2014 - March 2017: Radisson Blue Hotels and Resorts

Executive Housekeeper

Pre-Opening team member.

Worked as executive housekeeper. Responsible for housekeeping operations and ordering of new linens, uniforms, chemicals, equipment's, and housekeeping general supplies. Keeping track of all the work areas & maintain quality work as per company standards. Worked closely with the project managers and engineering team for installing laundry machines and other necessary equipment's. Carried out the complex routine operations for standard operating procedures for rooms divisions. Rebuilding of standard operating procedure.

May 2013 - September 2013: Fairfield by Marriott

Room Operations Manager

Opened first brand in Asia and was a part of pre-opening team. Also responsible to take well equipped ready rooms without any snagging or breakdowns. Everything was well executed according to the company requirements and policies.

January 2012 - April 2013: Marriott International

Executive Housekeeper

Pre-opening team member.

Worked as executive housekeeper. Responsible for housekeeping operations and managing teams within the department. Taking handover of the ready rooms and public spaces, ordering the guest supplies and chemicals. Implemented various checklists and schedules for pre-opening of hotel.

February 2011 – December 2011: Marriott International

Laundry Manager

Pre-opening team member.

Responsible for day to day laundry operations, maintaining quality of work. Maintaining all the laundry machines & equipment's. Keeping track of chemicals for washing.

July 2009 to January 2011: Park Hyatt Resorts and Spa Goa

Assistant Laundry Manager.

Carried out daily housekeeping and laundry operations. Assisted laundry manager with all the operations in regards to housekeeping department.

August 2008 to September 2009: Courtyard by Marriott

Housekeeping Executive

Responsible for inspecting guest rooms and make a performance log for the improvement of the assigned team leaders & their team.

May 2006 to June 2008: The Oberoi Grand Hotel

Supervisor - Laundry / Housekeeping

Worked as laundry & housekeeping supervisor. Responsible for housekeeping & laundry operations. Supervised executive housekeeping manager for the hotel housekeeping operations.

Key Points

- Ultimately responsible for ensuring that all the rooms operations were carried out professionally
 as per the brand standards, and the highest level of services while maintaining the financial
 impact of such decisions and operations.
- Drives guest satisfaction by maintaining product service and quality standards, periodic property inspection, ensuring completion of brand and company training programs and initiating corrective actions as necessary.
- Develop and maintain hotel operating policies, procedures, and standards of each brand.
- Ensure responsible financial management of assigned hotels at all times.
- Inspecting every guest room including VIP rooms in order to provide zero defect linen in guest rooms and public areas.
- Inspecting each guest room including VIP rooms in order to provide zero defect Rooms and Public Areas.
- Inspecting all renovated public area, rooms and ensuring that they are defect free before releasing.
- Planning the various schedules for different areas (Housemen cleaning schedules, Room Attendant extra cleaning schedules and the schedules related to for the specified areas).
- Interviewing & hiring new permanent and contractual staff.

- Maintaining the Standard Operating Procedures and cross checking that the same is followed within the staff at all levels.
- Maintaining technical competence through Resource management (Planning and prioritizing resource utilization and progress monitoring).
- Maintaining the leadership skills through communication of values, motivation, team building and integration of different culture.
- Initiated the improvisation of the floor sheen and quality with efforts to maintain the marble in guest bathrooms of all 365 rooms, ongoing efforts for lobby, restaurants, cloak rooms, banquet halls to a 90% gloss level achievement.
- Have been able to control waste and pilferage by defining objectives with regard to operating procedures on floors following quality inspections.
- Imparting training to staff, helping them work in a team, increasing levels of interaction and coaching them.
- Helping the staff to develop through constant feedback and creating opportunities to help them grow.
- Maintaining cross-functional collaboration through internal relations.
- Planning the various schedules for different areas.
- Complaint handling and service recovery for the same for 100 % guest satisfaction.
- Make budgets as per consumption figures of the previous year and exercise control measures.
- Maintain positive guest ratings, monitor and revert to comments immediately after investigation.
- Practice and value the core spirit and operating rules of the organization.
- Making decision through proper data analysis and approaching at a judgment after checking longterm view.
- Maintaining the leadership skills through communication of values, motivation, team building and integration of different culture.
- Maintaining the high levels of commitment, self-motivation, reliability and business ethics.
- Attending meetings with other staff members for resolving their issues.
- Conducting Performance Appraisal for the staff members, evaluating their competence levels against their success criteria and providing them with their new key result areas.
- Control of variable and non-variable cost for the department, preventive maintenance schedules with engineering.
- Managing team of 85 staff members.
- Exchange of linen and uniform monitored strictly with control on discards.
- Laundry operations in regards to washing, pressing, valet service, calendaring strictly followed in adherence to the standard operating procedures.
- Scheduling routine inspections of all Laundry areas with Laundry supervisors.
- Inspecting guest and public areas on a regular basis to ensure that the furnishings, facilities, and
 equipment are clean and in good repair and making recommendations for the upkeep of the
 same.
- Communicating clearly with all relevant internal departments on issues of linen and uniforms.
- Supervising outside contractors to ensure contractual compliance.
- Implementing and controlling Laundry procedures that provide for the health and safety of personnel and guests, such as Laundry chemicals and equipment's88, security and emergency procedures and environmental procedures.
- Planning for future staffing needs, involvement in the recruitment process, orientation and training of new members of the team.
- Maintaining effective team roster and leave schedules.
- Preparing and managing of the room budgets, including expense forecasting in line with hotel occupancy and forecasts.
- Implementing and maintaining strict health and safety policies and procedures.
- Maintaining stock of Linen, uniforms, fabrics and chemicals ensuring cost effective purchasing whilst maintaining brand standards.
- Attend all mandatory Off-job and departmental training courses as allocated in the development plan.

• Identifying and suggesting ways that can improve the laundry operations.

⇒ Demonstrated excellence in the following operations:

- Appreciated for getting 100% rating for GSS in Guest Rooms and Public Area in "The Leading Quality Assurance Audit" three times.
- Outsourced laundry and taken laundry revenue up by 55%.
- Appreciated for getting 98% above rating for Rooms, Public Area in "The Leading Quality Assurance Audit" at Marriott International Jaipur.
- Achieved the SPA & Wellness revenue up by 35%.
- Achieved 98% in LQA audit for two times in a row.
- Managed to get employ retention less than 2% during pre-opening of hotel.

Education and Professional Qualification

- Bachelor of Hotel Management and Catering Technology from OsmaniaUniversity, Hyderabad, A.P,INDIA (2001-2004)
- 12th from Board of Intermediate, Hyderabad (199-2001)
- Secondary schooling from Nalanda public School, Rc Puram, AP Hyderabad(1999)
- Computer Skills: Opera, Lotus notes 7, Fidelio, Espresso, MS Word, Excel & Power Point
- Capable at overseeing Housekeeping operations to ensure that job standards are met.
- Organizing & conducting Personality Development Program for staff & workers and introducing multi-skill training system.
- Capable of handling people of different age groups, maintaining healthy employee relations, thus providing a healthy and amicable working environment in the department.
- Capable of handling large employee workforce and maintaining disciplined & organized environment.
- Providing technical, behavioral and motivational training classes for the permanent and contractual staff in order to help, grow the performance level of the team, department and the organization overall.

Miscellaneous certificates and courses

- •OERC Academy Dg Approved Institute Mumbai- Basic STCW 2010 courses
- Certified by State of Alaska, Department of Public Safety Division Bureau of Fire Accreditation, Standards and Training for "Fire Behavior and Portable Fire Extinguishment Practices"

- Familiar with Fidelio Hotel Management System.
- Familiar with Opera Hotel Management System.
- Familiar with MXP operating system.
- Intermediate user of all Microsoft packages including excel, word, and power point. Advanced user of internet servers and email systems, including outlook.

Additional Information

Date of Birth31-05-1983

Marital Status Single

Languages knownEnglish, Hindi, & Telugu.

Passport noNO121352

Permanent Address Bonsai Homes Block B1 Tower 3 Flat no 117
Tellapur R.C Puram,
Hyderabad, Telangana State